# Aleksandr Kim

#### LEAD / SENIOR DATA SCIENTIST

London UK

🛮 +44 7555 850960 | 🗷 aleksandr.v.kim@gmail.com | 🧥 alexkimds.github.io | 🛅 aleksandrkim

## Summary .

Experienced Data Scientist with a background in leading projects and teams, and in applying data-backed solutions to complex business issues. My journey has progressed from being an Individual Contributor to a Team Leader, and then to working in a diverse international environment. I am always focused on creating tangible customer-oriented solutions through Data Science, rather than just enhancing ML metrics.

#### **Skills and Tools**

Soft Skills Team leading, mentoring, project management, presentation skill

Python (ML/DL libs), Docker, Airflow, Git, Flask, FastAPI, Cloud computing (AWS, Databricks)

**Data Mining** PySpark, Hadoop, SQL, Parsing (Scrapy, Selenium, Beautiful Soup)

**Data Visualization** Matplotlib, Seaborn, Plotly, Bokeh etc.

Solving ML tasks NLP, Uplift-modeling, Ranking, Matching, Dynamic pricing, TS Forcasting

**Analyzing Results** Validation/Time Series Validation, AB Testing

> Languages English (fluent), Russian (native), Hebrew (basic), German (basic)

## Work Experience

#### Intuit Inc. (Leading Financial Software Company)

London / Tel Aviv

SENIOR DATA SCIENTIST

2022 - Present

- Leveraged LLMs and classical ML models to enhance UX for millions of online users
- Moved to London and switched to a product team
- Optimized a complex data aggregation system using ML, reducing the error rate by 40%
- Organized and led Data Science Guild, uniting machine learning professionals and enthusiasts across whole Israeli site to foster collaboration and knowledge sharing

#### X5 Retail Group (top Russian retailer, about 20k stores)

Moscow

TEAM LEADER IN TWO DATA SCIENCE TEAMS

2021 - 2022

- Built a production-ready ML-based promotions optimization system (new product launch + internal SLA increase)
- Hired and leaded team of DS and DE specialists
- Organized data quality monitoring for Hive data bases

## Kaspersky (international cybersecurity company)

Moscow 2019 - 2021

DATA SCIENTIST

- Developed and Deployed BERT-based model for customers support automation (20% reduce of support costs)
- Analyzed user's behavior data, generated hypotheses and conducted AB tests to verify them (customers' Retention Rate increase)
- Developed and Deployed language identification model for customer's support (SLA increase + automation)

## Raiffeisen Bank (international bank)

Moscow

ANALYST

2018 - 2019

- Improved local compliance scoring system (significant revenue growth)
- Developed model for customer identification (employees' workload optimization)

# Digital Diesel Ltd. (diesel equipment service)

Moscow 2017 - 2018

Analyzed market of suppliers and created model to forecast suppliers' prices

Other projects 2018 - 2023

- RAG project with a Telegram Bot UI
- Freelance project for an energy supplying company: overdue payments prediction model
- Hackathon "human capital convention": Best task solution award (employee job description matching)

#### **Education**

#### MIPT (Moscow Institute of Physics and Technology, leading Russian university in STEM)

Moscow

MASTER'S DEGREE IN APPLIED MATHEMATICS AND PHYSICS

2016 - 2018

• Thesis: Distributed Support Vector Machines with Privileged Information

#### BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN APPLIED MATHEMATICS AND PHYSICS

2012 - 2016

• Thesis: Research of Quadratic Mappings. Building a Border of Image Set of Non Convex Functions